

BILL HRONIS, PMP

bill.hronis@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/billhronis/

PROFILE

A strategic project management leader with over 10 years of progressive experience overseeing highly visible projects aligned with corporate objectives. Leads, mentors, and coaches high-performing teams, while establishing positive work environments to drive organizational success and high employee engagement. Demonstrated ability in developing and implementing project management and governance processes that result in improved efficiencies and reduced costs. Known for strong leadership, innovative problem solving, building relationships with stakeholders, and driving consensus to propel organizations forward.

Areas of Expertise:

- Portfolio, Program and Project Management
- Leadership and Team Development
- Strategic Planning and Alignment
- Stakeholder Management
- Problem Resolution

- JIRA and Confluence
- Project Online and Power BI
- Waterfall and Agile Methodologies
- Communication and Interpersonal Skills
- Prioritization

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CI INVESTMENTS INC 2000 – 2020

Director, Project Management Office (PMO), 2018 - 2020

Led a team of eight program and project managers within the PMO, overseeing individual and team development, motivation, and performance. Oversaw team members in the planning, development, and execution of initiatives tied to strategic corporate objectives.

- Mentored non-PMO project managers within various IT departments companywide on project management
 practices implemented by the PMO to help strengthen overall project management maturity and improve project
 success rates.
- Partnered with executive project sponsors in the development of project business cases by identifying expected
 value and benefits realization to prioritize projects that generated greater value while increasing accountability and
 the odds of project success.
- Collaborated with the C-suite to identify areas of improvement in project management and overall PMO process improvements. Developed enhanced project initiation tools, implemented the use of both Agile and Waterfall methodologies, enhanced portfolio reporting tools, and standardized project reporting. This improved efficiencies in project execution, management, and reporting.
- Prepared and delivered quarterly portfolio status updates to C-suite, including progress and risk factors. Provided them with the required information to ensure that the portfolio remained aligned with corporate strategy and within their risk appetite.
- Developed and implemented a digitally automated end-to-end project intake process which reduced the time, complexity, and probability of human error in the writing, approval, and intake of project requests. This process automation reduced the time of completion from weeks to just seconds.
- Designed and implemented a PMO project governance structure which elevated the standards for all projects with PMO oversight.
- Developed and implemented a custom, interactive project dashboard using Microsoft Power BI, which effectively communicated the status of the full portfolio of projects to the C-suite and enabled them to drill down to program and project-specific data, increasing project status visibility by 100%.
- Created a project portfolio review and selection process to evaluate project alignment with corporate strategy to effectively remove bias from the project prioritization and selection process.

Program Manager, PMO, 2013 - 2018

Managed both high-risk and high-profile programs to achieve business needs using both Waterfall and Agile methodologies. Oversaw IT project managers and project team members during project execution to ensure project documents were updated weekly based on progress. Facilitated project meetings for all project activities including steering committee updates.

- Assumed responsibility for a program that was two years past due and over \$5M in sunk cost and led the team to a successful rebuild and launch within six months.
- Led the first major project within the organization which showcased the benefits of agile development which led to widespread adoption of agile methodologies throughout development teams companywide.
- Completed various medium to large business programs and projects tied to corporate objectives from project initiation to project close, helping to achieve business objectives.
- Liaised with various departments including IT silos, Product, Marketing, Legal, and Communications to ensure common understanding and commitment to project objectives.
- Designated a Microsoft Project Team specialist to assist team members with challenges, roadblocks, and questions
 related to using and operating MS Project. Led to improved effectiveness on the team and meeting project
 objectives and sponsor expectations.
- Led projects for the most demanding project sponsors within the organization to ensure an orderly and organized project execution while meeting project objectives.

Manager, Product Development and Governance, 2007 – 2013

Identified and maintained the required infrastructure for both new and existing investment products. Led projects that impacted multiple business units and subsidiaries, while maintaining a cost-effective approach. Assisted with the development of new product features and the implementation of product enhancements to achieve desired objectives of both internal and external partners.

- Developed, implemented, and managed segregated fund products, generating over \$1B in sales while working closely with insurance partners to ensure available products met client needs.
- Created and deployed training materials for the organization (entry-level to C-suite) to ensure a consistent and comprehensive understanding of new product offerings that drove ongoing sales success.
- Provided creative solutions to product issues and gathered information on customer experiences to spearhead future product enhancements.

EDUCATION

PROJECT MANAGEMENT INSTITUTE

Project Management Professional Certification (PMP), 2022

UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO, SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES

Full Stack Development Bootcamp Certificate, 2021 Leading Projects in Organizations Certificate, 2014 Foundations of Project Management Certificate, 2013

GEORGIAN COLLEGE

Coaching and Motivation Seminar, 2007

RYERSON UNIVERSITY (now Toronto Metropolitan University)

Management and Leadership Development / LIFO Certificate, 2006

PODIUM CONSULTING INC.

Podium Presentation Skill Certificate, 2004

CENTENNIAL COLLEGE

Marketing Diploma, 2000